The Catalogue of Britten Manuscripts: Musical compositions of Benjamin Britten
British Library
- Benjamin Britten: 'War Requiem', op. 66, 1961-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60609-60610; 2 volumes
  - Benjamin Britten: 'War Requiem', op. 66 (short score), 1961-1979; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60609; 1 volume (102 folios)
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60609
    Publication Note
    The discarded draft fragments (ff. 69-101) are considerd by Philip Reed, in Mervyn Cooke, Britten: 'War Requiem'(1996), pp. 20-48, passim.
  - Benjamin Britten: 'War Requiem', op. 66 (full score), 1961; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60610; 1 volume (137 folios)
    Partially autograph music manuscript, in pencil and in black ink, including the hands of two copyists (Imogen Holst and Rosamund Strode) - see Philip Reed, in Mervyn Cooke, Britten: 'War Requiem'(1996), p. 46.
    Dated (Holst's hand): 'Aldeburgh, December 20th 1961' (f. 137), and annotated (in the same hand) with instructions to the copyist on ff. 101, 105, 120, 130.
    Title page 'Requiem aeternam', including brief note by Britten on the harp (f. 1).
    1. 'Requiem aeternam' (ff. 2-13).
    2. 'Dies irae' (ff. 14-52v).
    3. 'Offertorium' (ff. 53-76).
    Title page 'Sanctus and Agnus Dei' (f. 77).
    4. 'Sanctus' (ff. 78-94v).
    5. 'Agnus Dei' (ff. 95-100).
    6. 'Libera me' (ff. 101-137).
    Not British Library binding. Folio dimensions: 545 x 340 mm. With smaller pasted-down ff. 97. 98, 131, 132, 135, and 136. There are brown 'splash' stains on f. 15-15v.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60610
- Benjamin Britten: 'Symphony for Cello and Orchestra', op. 68, 1963; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60611; 1 volume (74 folios)
  Full score. Music manuscript, in pencil, on two sets of folios of different size bound together. Partly autograph.
  Dated, in Britten's hand: 'Aldeburgh May 3rd 1963' (f. 74v). Also dated twice [by Boosey & Hawkes]: 'received 24.4.63' (ff. 1 and 30).
  Title and dedication: 'Cello Symphony / Score I / For Mstislav Rostropovich' (f. 1)
  I Allegro maestoso(ff. 2-29)
  title: 'Cello Symphony / Score / II' (f. 30)
  II Presto inquieto(ff. 31-44)
  title: 'III' (f. 45)
  III Adagio(ff. 46-57v)
  folio 58 not used
  title: 'Cello Symphony / IV' (f. 59)
  [IV] Passacaglia: Andante allegro (ff. 60-74v).
  Not British Library binding. Stamped on front cover: 'Boosey & Hawkes Hire Library'. Folio dimensions: 365 x 270 mm (ff. 1-29); 450 x 290 mm (ff. 30-74).
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60611
- Benjamin Britten: 'Curlew River', op. 71, 1964; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60612-60613; 2 volumes
  A short score and a partly autograph full score.
  Libretto: William Plomer, from the medieval Japanese Nō play Sumidagawa by Jūrō Motomasa.
  First performance: 12 June 1964, Orford Church, Aldeburgh Festival. First broadcast: 21 June 1964 (BBC Third Programme).
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Curlew River', op. 71 (short score), 1964; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60612; 1 volume (55 folios)
    An autograph short score, in pencil (ff. 1-44v), together with discarded autograph draft material (ff. 46-55).
    With Britten's initials on the title page (f. 1).
    The music in the draft material has been identified (and annotated in pencil by the Britten-Pears Library) at the foot of ff. 46, 47, 49, 50, 51, 52, 53, 54, and 55.
    Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm. With a patch of scribble in blue ink at the foot of f. 46.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60612
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Curlew River', op. 71 (full score), 1964; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60613; 1 volume (398 folios)
    A partially autograph music manuscript, in pencil, with pasted-down additions in black ink for voice and chorus.
    Dated, in Britten's hand: 'Score finished / Maundy Thursday / March 1964' (f. 396).
    For tenor, two baritones, treble and bass voices, with the following 'Instrumentalists' indicated (f. 1v): 'Flute (doubling Piccolo) / Horn (in F - written in C) / Viola / Double bass / Harp / Percussion [further explication also given by Britten] / Chamber organ'.
    Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm. Includes a number of smaller, pasted-down folios.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60613
- Benjamin Britten: 'Songs & Proverbs of William Blake', op. 74, 1965; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60614; 1 volume (25 folios)
  For baritone and piano. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, dated, in Britten's hand: 'April 6th 1965' (f. 24).
  The title page (f. 1) shows faint traces of the work's original title ('Songs & Sentences') which Britten erased before writing 'Songs & Proverbs'. The texts, from William Blake, were 'selected by Peter Pears'. The title page is also signed by Britten and includes, at the top of the folio, his dedication to Dietrich Fischer-Dieskau: 'For Dieter - the past and the future'.
  The rejected term 'Sentences' is also used (f. 1v) in Britten's list of the the texts, which alternate between passages from Proverbs of Hell (in the final extract, from Auguries of Innocence) and poems from the Songs of Experience.
  'Sentence[s] I': 'The pride of the peacock...' (f. 2-2v)
  'London' (ff. 2v-4v)
  'Sentences II': 'Prisons are built with stones of law...' (f. 4v)
  'The Chimney-Sweeper' (ff. 4v-6)
  'Sentences III': 'The bird a nest...' (f. 6v)
  'A Poison-Tree' (ff. 6v-9), of which ff. 7v-9 are 'discarded' (see pencil notes by Britten-Pears Library at the bottom of each page)
  for the revised section of 'A Poison-Tree', see ff. 10v-14 (of which, f. 13 is scored in blue ink)
  'Sentences IV': 'Think in the morning...' (f. 14)
  'The Tyger' (ff. 14v-16v)
  'Sentences V': 'The tygers of wrath...' (f. 17)
  'The Fly' (ff. 17v-19)
  'Sentences VI' (f. 19-19v)
  'Ah! Sun-flower' (ff. 19v-22)
  'Sentences VII': 'To see a world in a grain of sand...' (f. 22)
  'Every Night and every Morn' (ff. 22-24).
  f. 25-25v comprises draft material relating to 'Every Night and every Morn'.
  Britten has added a brief footnote to Rosamund [Strode], copyist, on f. 11v.
  Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm (ff. 12 and 13 are smaller insertions). On the following folios, some staves have been extended in blue ink: ff. 3, 4, 4v, 5, 5v, 7, 7v, 8, 8v, 11v, 13 (which is also scored in blue ink), 14, 14v, 17v, 18, 18v, 20, 20v, and 22v.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60614
- Benjamin Britten: 'Children's Crusade', op. 82, 1968-1969; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60615-60616; 2 volumes
  In two volumes, an autograph short score and a partly autograph full score.
  Text by Bertolt Brecht. Set in German, and set separately in English (translation by Hans Keller).
  First performance: 19 May 1969, St Paul's Cathedral, London (relayed by BBC Radio 3).
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Children's Crusade', op. 82 (short score), 1968; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60615; 1 volume (36 folios)
    Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, including discarded passages. Dated by Britten: 'November 10th 1968' (f. 20v).
    Title page (f. 1): 'Kinderkreuzzug 1939 (Brecht) / For Boy's [sic] voices (solo & chorus) / 2 pianos & percussion / (with electric organ to support voices)'
    list of voice parts (f. 1v)
    setting in German (ff. 2-20v)
    discarded draft passages (ff. 21-26v), identified in pencil at the foot of folios by Britten-Pears Library
    title page: 'Voice part' (f. 27)
    voice parts set in English (ff. 28-31v)
    inserted verse, in English, with date '20 Nov. 68' at the head of the folio (f. 32)
    continuation of voice parts set in English (ff. 33-36).
    Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm, except f. 11 (230 x 270 mm) and f. 14 (a small hinged addition to f. 13v).
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60615
    Benjamin Britten, Children's Crusade (Kinderkreuzzug) Op. 82 (London: Faber & Faber, 1973). A limited facsimile edition of the short score, including twelve colour illustrations from a series of paintings based on the work by Sidney Nolan.
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Children's Crusade', op. 82 (full score), 1968-1969; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60616; 1 volume (48 folios)
    A partly autograph music manuscript, in pencil, setting a text by Bertolt Brecht (translated by Hans Keller). Signed and dated by Britten: 'Aldeburgh October-November 1968' (f. 1), with an additional folio dated in a copyist's hand: 'Sept. '69' (f. 48).
    title page (f. 1), at the head of which Britten has recorded that the work was written for 'members of Wandsworth School choir and orchestra (director Russell Burgess) to perform on the 50th Anniversary of Save the Children Fund at St Paul's Cathedral, May 19th 1969', and described the work as 'A Ballad for children's voices & orchestra'
    abbreviated German title: 'K[inder]K[reuzzug]' (f. 2)
    an extensive composer's note referring to notation voicing, to percussion groups, and to the probable necessity for two conductors (f. 2v)
    'Children's Crusade' (ff. 4-47v), including the English translation within the score
    an additional folio (f. 48) dated 'Sept. '69': 'Amendments to vocal line put into dylined full score used as German text Master Copy' (not in Britten's hand).
    Folio dimensions: 455 x 290 mm, except f. 48 (380 x 280 mm).
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60616
- Benjamin Britten: 'Third Suite for Cello', op. 87, 1971-1974; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60617; 1 volume (13 folios)
  An autograph score, in pencil, signed by Britten on the title page (f. 2), and dated 'Feb. 23 - March 3 1971 / Aldeburgh' (f. 12v).
  The work is dedicated to Mstislav Rostropovich: 'For Slava' (f. 2). Rostropovich gave the first performance (21 December 1974) at Snape Maltings Concert Hall.
  a note (typescript) from Britten ('B.B. / Summer, 1971') concerning the three Russian folk songs on which the work is based (f. 1)
  title page, with Britten's signature and his dedication to Mstislav Rostropovich (f. 2)
  revised passage: 'Alternative to 1st 7 bars' (f. 2v)
  the same revised passage of music in black ink (copyist hand), dated at the head of the folio: 'Jan. 74' (f. 3)
  a note in pencil (f. 4), made by the Britten-Pears Library, highlighting two revised passages (f. 3 and f. 5)
  the second revised passage, also the opening bars (f. 5)
  I 'Lento (introduzione)' (ff. 6-7)
  II 'Tranquillo' (f. 7-7v)
  III 'Con moto (canto)' (f. 7v)
  IV 'Lento (barcarola)' (ff. 7v-8)
  V 'Allegretto (dialogo)' (f. 8-8v)
  VI 'Andante expressivo (fuga)' (f. 9-9v)
  VII 'Fantastico (recitativo)' (f. 9v)
  VIII 'Presto (moto perpetuo)' (f. 10)
  IX 'Lento solenne (passacaglia)', beginning at the end of f. 9v (repeated and struck-through at the end of f. 10) and continuing ff. 11-12v
  draft passages (f. 13).
  On f. 12, there are four indications of mood or expression that appear in both conventional Italian and in the Russian alphabet (capitals). Paul Banks (ed.), Benjamin Britten: A Catalogue of the Published Works (1999) notes (p. 143) that when Rostropovich visited Aldeburgh in January 1974 (which matches the date at the head of the revised passage on f. 3), he played the work to the composer and edited the published score.
  Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm, except f. 1 (250 x 205 mm) and f. 3 (195 x 275 mm).
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60617
- Benjamin Britten: Canticle V 'The Death of Saint Narcissus', op. 89, 1974; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60618; 1 volume (9 folios)
  An autograph score, in pencil, for tenor and harp, dated 'Horham July 1974' (f. 9).
  The text is taken from the poem 'The Death of Saint Narcissus' by T. S. Eliot, and the work is dedicated to William Plomer.
  the text (typescript) of 'The Death of Saint Narcissus' [by T. S. Eliot] (ff. 1-2, with annotations in pencil)
  title page, with Britten's initials, and his dedication: 'In loving memory of William Plomer' (f. 3)
  brief notation, struck-through (f. 3v)
  the music, in score (ff. 4-9).
  First performance: 15 January 1975, Schloss Elmau, Upper Bavaria (Peter Pears and Osian Ellis).
  Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm, except f. 1 and f. 2 (290 x 205 mm).
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60618
- Benjamin Britten: 'Sacred and Profane', op. 91, 1974-1975; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60619; 1 volume (17 folios)
  Eight medieval lyrics for unaccompanied voices (SSATB). Autograph music manuscript, in pencil. Signed, and dated 'Dec 1974 - Jan 1975' (f. 2).
  title page ('Mediaeval Lyrics / Sacred & Profane'), with Britten's initials and his dedication: 'For P[eter]P[ears] & the Wilbye Consort' (f. 1)
  second title page ('Sacred & Profane / 8 Mediaeval Lyrics for 5 Voices') with Britten's signature, the dedication repeated, and a note at the bottom of the folio that the sequence of the lyrics should be attacca, breaking briefly between lyrics 5 and 6 if required (f. 2)
  1. 'St Godric's Hymn' (f. 3-3v)
  2. 'I mon waxe wode' (f. 4-4v)
  3. 'Lenten is Come' (ff. 5-6v)
  4. 'The Long Night' (ff. 7-8)
  5. 'Yif Ic of Luve Can' (f. 9-9v)
  6. 'Carol' (ff. 10-11), dated 'Dec 30th'
  7. 'Ye that passen by' (f. 12-12v)
  8. 'A Death' (ff. 13-16), dated 'Jan 9th 1974' (the year conflicts with dating elsewhere in the manuscript and it would appear that Britten intended '1975').
  First performance: 14 September 1975, Snape Maltings Concert Hall (the Wilbye Consort, Peter Pears conducting).
  Folio dimensions: 380 x 280 mm, except f. 15 (115 x 180 mm) which is hinged and attached to f. 14v.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60619
- Benjamin Britten: 'String Quartet No. 3', op. 94, 1975; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60620; 1 volume (17 folios)
  Score. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil, with Britten's initials to the title page (f. 1). Dated: 'Suffolk-Venice - Oct. Nov. 1975' (f. 16).
  title page, with Britten's initials (f. 1)
  I 'Duets: With moderate movement' (ff. 2-4v)
  II 'Ostinato: Very fast' (ff. 5-7)
  III 'Solo: Very calm' (ff. 8-9)
  IV 'Burlesque: Fast - con fuoco' (ff. 10-12)
  V 'Recit. & Passacaglia (La Serenissima): Slow' (ff. 13-16), dated 'Nov. 20 / 1975' at the foot of f. 15v
  discarded draft material (f. 17v).
  First performance: 19 December 1976, Snape Maltings Concert Hall (Amadeus Quartet).
  Folio dimensions: 285 x 295 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60620
- Benjamin Britten: Music for the documentary film Night Mail, 1936; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60621; 1 volume (24 folios)
  Night Mail is a short documentary film produced by the General Post Office (G.P.O.) Film Unit about the London, Midland and Scottish Railway mail train making its journey north, from London to Scotland. Britten's contribution included the title music and the music for the end sequence, which was accompanied by a reading of verses written especially for the film by W. H. Auden, beginning 'This is the Night Mail crossing the border'.
  An autograph full score, in ink (with red and blue crayon), for flute, oboe, trumpet, percussion, harp, and string quartet.
  Dated (in pencil), with Britten's initials: 'Jan. 12th 1936' (f. 20v).
  title page, in pencil (f. 1)
  title music (ff. 2-4)
  second sequence, incorporating various incidental sounds ('compressed air', 'sandpaper on slate', clanking and drilling noises, a whistle, hammering, and 'coal falling down a shaft') and the start of the commentary (ff. 5-6v)
  end sequence, incorporating text by Auden: 'This is the night mail crossing the border / Bringing the cheque and the postal order...' (ff. 7-20v)
  passage for trumpet, scored in pencil (f. 21)
  rhythmic notation (in pencil) of Auden's opening lines (f. 22)
  trumpet part (two bars only), in pencil (f. 23)
  trumpet part with other instruments (six bars), in ink (f. 24-24v).
  The music was recorded by an ensemble conducted by Britten, 15 January 1936. First broadcast: BBC TV, 16 October 1949. First concert performance: 7 November 1997, Conway Hall, London.
  Folio dimensions: 355 x 260 mm.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60621
  For the full text of Auden's poem (dated July 1935), see Edward Mendelson (ed.), The English Auden: Poems, Essays and Dramatic Writings 1927-1939 (London: Faber and Faber, 1977), pp. 290-2.
- Benjamin Britten: Incidental music for The Ascent of F6, [1937]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60622; 1 volume (48 folios)
  Incidental music for The Ascent of F6, a stage play by W. H. Auden and Christopher Isherwood.
  Signed by Britten on ff 1, 1v, 3, and 47. The volume is not dated.
  Full autograph score, in ink (with some additions in pencil and red crayon), for voices (SATB), percussion, ukulele, and two pianos, as follows:
  signed title page, in red crayon (f. 1)
  'Music to Group Theatre production of Ascent of F6' (a numbered list, in ink, of the sequence of compositions), and a note in pencil of the published scores available, stamped 'Boosey & Hawkes Rental Library' (ff. 1v-2)
  'I Overture', signed by Britten (ff. 3-11v)
  'IIA' and 'IIB', 'Entr'actes for Mr & Mrs A' (f. 12)
  'III Entr'acte & Gunn's Song' (f. 13-13v)
  'IV Pantomime & Mother's Song' (ff. 14-17v)
  'V Chant' (f. 18)
  'VIA Climbing Music' (f. 19)
  'VIB Climbing Music' (f. 20)
  'VIC Funeral March and Chorus (off)' (ff. 21-23)
  'VII Gunn's Song' (f. 24)
  'VIII Caberet [sic] Jazz Song' (ff. 25-38)
  'IX Mother's song with chorus' (ff. 39-42)
  text fragment, partly struck-through with red crayon (f. 42v)
  'F6 Blues / ask the court to be cleared', beginning with Auden's text 'Stop all the clocks' (ff. 43-46v)
  'Prelude to Act II' (ff. 47-48).
  First performance: 26 February 1937, Mercury Theatre, London. First broadcast: BBC TV, 18 September 1938. First broadcast with complete score: BBC National, 5 December 1938.
  Folio dimensions: 360 x 260 mm, except for several small pasted down or hinged folios (ff. 22, 23, 26, 28, 30, 31, 32, 34, 35, 36, and 38. A number of folios have been repaired with clear adhesive tape.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60622
  For the poem beginning 'Stop all the clocks' by W. H. Auden, from which the lyrics of 'Caberet Song' (ff. 25-38) are partly drawn, see Edward Mendelson (ed.), The English Auden: Poems, Essays and Dramatic Writings 1927-1939 (London: Faber and Faber, 1977), p. 163.
- Benjamin Britten: Incidental music for The Dark Tower, [1945]; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60623; 1 volume (iii + 13 folios)
  Incidental music for the radio play The Dark Tower by Louis MacNeice. Signed by Britten on the title page (f. 1). The manuscript is not dated.
  Full score, autograph, in pencil (with additions in red crayon) for trumpet in C, percussion and strings, as follows:
  front cover with title, exhibiting various annotations indicating prior BBC Music Library custody (f. i, with f. ii hinged)
  title page, signed (f. 1)
  score, with 16 divisions indicated by Roman numerals in red crayon (ff. 2-12)
  on f. 13v and f. iii are brief notes recording previous borrowings from the BBC Music Library.
  First performance: 21 January 1946, BBC Home Service.
  Folio dimensions: 365 x 270 mm, except f. ii (25 x 70 mm) which is hinged and attached to f. i). Volume originally held by the BBC Music Library, with their ownership stamps on ff. i, 2, 6, 8v, and 12.
  Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60623
- Benjamin Britten: Juvenilia, 1925; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60624-60625; 2 manuscript notebooks
  Two manuscript notebooks containing music written by Britten in his youth. The music comprises waltzes for piano and a Sonata in D Major for violin and piano.
  - Benjamin Britten: Waltzes for piano, 1925; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60624; 1 notebook (ii + 18 folios)
    Ten waltzes for piano, followed by a 'Waltz Duet' and a 'Petite Valse'. Autograph music manuscript, in pencil (except for f. 1 and the first stave of f. 1v, which are in ink).
    front cover (dated 'March 1925') entitled: 'Walztes [sic] / composed / by / Edward Benjamin Britten / Opus 3 / 1925 / dedicated to My Father: / R. V. Britten Esq.' (f. i)
    Waltz 1 (ff. 1-2v)
    Waltz 2 (ff. 3-4)
    Waltz 3 (ff. 4-6)
    Waltz 4 (ff. 6-9)
    Waltz 5 (ff. 9-10)
    Waltz 6 (ff. 10v-11)
    Waltz 7 (ff. 11v-12)
    Waltz 8 (ff. 12-13)
    Waltz 9 (ff. 13v-14)
    Waltz 10, mis-numbered as '9' and corrected by Britten as '10' (ff. 14v-15)
    'Waltz Duet' (ff. 15v-18)
    'Petite Valse' (f. 18v).
    Re-bound (sewn) music manuscript notebook (A. Weekes & Co. Ltd., 14 Hanover St, London) with original soft covers. Dimensions: 295 x 235 mm.
    Digitised copy available on British Library Digitised Manuscripts: http://www.bl.uk/manuscripts/FullDisplay.aspx?ref=Add_MS_60624
    In 1970, Britten published Five Walztes (retaining his original mis-spelling in the title), four of which were edited and revised from '10 Walztes' (1925) in manuscript, supplemented by a fifth Waltz (1923) from another manuscript source. See Paul Banks, Benjamin Britten: A Catalogue of the Published Works (1999), p. 3. See also, Christopher Mark, Early Benjamin Britten: A Study of Stylistic Evolution (1995), pp. 8-10. Mark reproduces Waltzes 1-2 and 5-9 (Appendix I, pp. 273-90). An arrangement of Waltz 6, Mark notes (p. 10), provided the 'scherzo' for Britten's Sonata in D Major for violin and piano (Add MS 60625) composed the following month.
  - Benjamin Britten: 'Violin Sonata in D Major', 1925; British Library: Music Collections; Add MS 60593-60626 - Add MS 60625; 1 notebook (ii + 17 folios)
    For violin and piano, in score. Autograph music manuscript, in ink and in pencil.
    Dated on the front cover: 'Begun March 1925'. The date on which the Sonata was finished is recorded on f. 13v and f. 17: 'April 6th 1925'. With Britten's (youthful) signature ('E B Britten') accompanying each date.
    The notebook comprises:
    front cover, entitled 'Violin Sonata in D Major', with date ('Begun March 1925'), with signature and dedication to Britten's brother, 'R. H. M. Britten' (f. i)
    'Allegro con brio' scored in ink (ff. 1-3v)
    'Adagio ma mon troppo' scored in ink (ff. 3v-5)
    'Scherzo' scored in ink (ff. 5-6)